they say that they're going to release
it and I'm just like when Please Release
it for Christmas please so that's funny
there's some large companies out there
who are sweating bullets right now just
knowing that their their credit card
flow is insecure just for the CSS
[Music]
release
all right everybody how's it going
Welcome to our last episode of the year
so uh we just wanted to give a really
big thank you and shout out to everybody
from the critical thinking Community all
of you who have been in there from day
one up until maybe this is even your
first episode um we just you know we
can't really thank you enough for
everything that you've done um it's been
amazing to see the community come
together and consume our podcast and
give us feedback and interact with
everybody and uh it's just been an
amazing year overall um we definitely
couldn't have asked for anything better
so you know shout out to you guys you
guys made this happen um you know thank
you to everybody in the Discord thank
you to everybody on YouTube thank you to
everybody on Spotify and apple podcast
and just everywhere it's it's been
amazing to see the outpour uh from the
bug bounding Community to our podcast
and it it really just uh is giving us
the signal that we need to keep doing
what we're doing so um you know thanks
again for all that and um we're really
looking forward to what's be going to be
coming in the next year um this episode
is really just a very chill sort of
recap for me and Justin we're going to
be going over our sort of year in review
uh the the trends that we had in our own
personal hacking experience some of the
things that we'd like to be doing next
year and moving forward and um yeah like
I said Thank you to everybody for
listening thanks for you know sharing
the podcast supporting us we really
appreciate it and uh we can't wait to
see what happens next year all right
we're rolling so so you saying saying 10
you have 10 gig now in your house yeah
so I mean technically I'm only getting
like 7.8 gig down and like four gig
up but I mean it could be worse 7.8 gig
down is that what you said per second
yes yeah yeah yeah per second holy crap
dude what' you have to do to get
that uh they wanted me to sign up
honestly they sent me uh they sent me a
letter in the mail they're like hey
were're you know this guy a
sucker they they sent out all these
things in the mail and they were like
you know speeds up to 10 gigs and I was
like holy crap you know we'll see about
that it's a local one to the Bay Area
called Sonic
wow that's crazy um yeah it's crazy so
dude it's $50 a month no way oh Oh I
thought you they were at least priced
that's that's cheaper than mine dude
that's what cheap it's cheaper than so I
used to pay
uh for a different ISP I used to get
1,000 down and I paid for higher upload
speed for 35 megabits up uh and I I paid
$85 a month for that that's what mine is
yeah and then I got this letter in the
mail they were like it speeds up to 10
gig I was like okay yeah yeah sure
whatever I look it up and uh you know
they're like oh yeah it's available in
your area 50 bucks a month three months
free like yeah okay whatever a he types
it into the search bar yeah I'm like
yeah we we'll see we see click the sign
up button
yeah cuz I'm always I always look for
you know a better deal if there's one
there so um and sure enough they had it
and they were like you know here's lay
lines and uh you know I signed up and
sure enough they they came and they they
installed like a a fiber termination box
andu I was going to say did they have to
like dig through your whole front yard
or something like that no so um they run
the fiber on the poles here uh because
we don't have like snow or anything like
that and uh they basically just cheed
off from the pole up to the like the
roof of my house and and they ran it
through my attic and down into my office
and they terminated it with an O just
like on the wall there's like there's a
fiber line like coming you have to cut
did you have to cut like a bunch of
holes in your wall no there's there's a
single drill hole that they put like a
little flange around and um the fiber
line just like runs along my ceiling
along the wall terminates here cuz I
don't have ethernet throughout my house
otherwise I would have done it somewhere
else um and then it just connects to my
server and my server pushes everything
out czy wow dude that's crazy your your
server rack behind you there has better
internet connection than in some
freaking data centers now yeah dude yeah
you could probably see so I've got um
I've got some really fancy fancy mancy
stuff here this is um this is a 24 Port
10 gig switch okay so it's got 24
ethernet ports and each ethernet port
puts out 10 gigs it does like 300 gig
per second throughput uh it can do 25
gig service you buy all of this recently
so so it cost you $50 to upgrade but
then you spent an extra ,000 in Hardware
in the first week yeah yeah no these two
these two are new these are these are
new fancy upgrades deal with it like
yeah so no yeah so so both of my
computers uh the best adapters that I
have do two and a half gig so I can
saturate those for sure like I've done
speed tests on my laptop at like 2 and
A2 gig uh the speeds that can get that
I'm getting right now are coming
directly from the Gateway um but uh yeah
I have I have cards adapters coming in
the mail that are that will give
me how much did you spend on all of the
crap surrounding your new 10 gig upgrade
also you're moving you're gonna be
moving in the next right right so okay
so so so here's the here's the thing um
you ain't going to get that the speeds
in East Coast man it's not going to
happen I I probably won't get the those
speeds from my ISP what what this does
do is it gives me internal 10 gig so my
whole internal network has 10 gig speeds
now so I can transfer files between my
Nas at 10 gig speeds I can transfer
things between devices all that kind of
stuff at 10 gig speeds which is a nice
cool if you have like a like a media
server or something like that which I do
yeah okay nice yeah um that's what that
is um and
then uh the hardware was about
$2,000 um oh my God the
upgade dude 10 stuff is expensive that's
more expensive than I was thinking man
what the heck I was I was getting ready
to cringe at you saying $500 no no no so
so the Gateway like the Gateway if it
was just the Gateway that would have
been 500 bucks the real expensive stuff
is when you start to have like multiple
terminations of 10 gig so just for some
context here and I know we're rambling a
little bit but we are but hey it's
Christmas time like a like a USB
Thunderbolt adapter for like a lap so
like a Mac right it has all USBC
Thunderbolt uh four ports or something
yeah an adapter for that that does 10
gig is
$250 oh my gosh yeah and like the all
the like the switching honestly like the
switches and stuff are cheaper than it
is to buy the adapters for the actual
end points like my PC is going to use a
PCI Express 10 gig adapter that's like
$70 that's not like too bad right like
that that's doable $250 for like that's
n you know it's crazy some of these
things are like really really expensive
just because it's not a widely used like
most people right like you could buy 2
and a half gig adapter readily most
people don't need more than two and a
half gig I contacted my ISP because I
was like hey I got like my I got my
equipment set up and I did test and I'm
not getting my full 10 gig speeds I'm
only getting like seven and a half down
and like four up and they were like okay
well like uh it look it looks like we're
we're delivering the full tent to you
but like I don't think anybody in your
area is going to have anything close to
that but let me look and like he looked
and he was like all right well nobody
has anything close to that but like the
closest I can find is somebody has an
ero that's got like two and a half gigs
symmetric and they're not having any
problems so you know let me know like if
you find what the problem I was like
they didn't expect you to go drop you
know freaking two grand on all the
equipment you needed to like call them
out on their [__] on their 10 10
gigs up and down that's for sure like I
I don't think most people have have this
level of equipment but um you know I
like I like fancy toys your your home
setup is pretty badass and your
automation set up and that sort of thing
it's pretty great so uh definitely makes
sense that you would invest in that and
since we're since we're already off
topic I might as well take us a little
bit further well this one's T tangent on
topic that I was just going to talk
about a little later um I'm GNA go ahead
and share my screen for anyone who is uh
following Along on YouTube um but dude
check this out so I recently um can can
you see my screen yet yep so I recently
set up um so sort of inspired by your uh
python based sort of encoding decoding
systems you know the various modules
you've set up over the years um I told
you I was working on my own sort of uh
keyboard shortcut um
oriented sort of utility system let's
call it that right where where you know
you can do uh URL encoding decoding
basic D4 encoding decoding and that sort
of thing and then I thought man this
would be really cool if it had a sort of
a UI based um portion of it right um and
so I I found this tool right here this
is called flow um and it's like a little
launcher and you can program it with
python modules and so I I wrote a bunch
of python I just installed it last night
but I wrote a bunch of python modules
for it and one of them is like this like
JWT right and then I can paste in a JWT
and it will go ahead and open it right
away in like jwo or something like that
right uh let me see if I can get it to
to show yeah like this right and then
it'll inject it right into jwo to make
it easy to see and I've got it doing
like um various hex parsing and URL
encoding and decoding really quickly and
one of the ones that I found the most
useful is this one check this one out so
I pop this open and I type mrr right
match and replace Rex and essentially
what it'll do is it'll allow me to uh
specify uh in the first parameter of
this it I'll specify a um and for those
of you listening it's just a small box
on my screen that's popping up and uh I
type a little command into it and it
will show me the output uh in that same
little box or copy it to my clipboard so
what this one does is it is it does uh
match and replace rex on what is in my
clipboard so I can say like okay um let
me go ahead and replace every uh you
know a character with a B character
right and if I like go ahead and just
copy this command and and run it now the
the contents of my clipboard is Mr rrbb
instead of M RAB right so like all of
the time when you're I'm trying to work
on stuff like I'm wanting to strip out
new line characters or I'm wanting to
like you know remove every character
that's not a number or something like
that and then I've got to either do it
manually I've got to write a little
python script for it and now I've just
kind of got this really easy plug-in
based um launcher system that will go
ahead and run all those match and
replace rexes for me and that sort of
thing and or and remove various you know
like for example the scenarios where you
need to remove a backslash right because
you're copying escaped Json into normal
Json so you can do that sort of thing um
and then some of the other things I've
got on my list that I haven't fully
built out yet is I want to have it like
quick query um quick query chat GPT uh
3.5 and be able to do that and I also
want to be able to have it do OCR
automatically where I I'll like have a
picture in my clipboard and then I'll
just hit like OCR and it will will take
all the text out of that picture and
copy it into my clipboard I just feel
like that' be super badass all right so
for OCR I have a thing for you it's um
there's a tool called power toys it's
actually written I think by Microsoft
this yeah power to the guy who yeah yeah
so he has um there's like an OCR utility
built into that that's open source
um so have you set up this power toys
run thing yeah I have it yeah oh nice um
yeah uh the other thing Jo why AR you
using this for for your like power toys
or flow or anything like that for your
encoding
modules um so there's a couple reasons
uh the main thing is it's extra overhead
so for for Mac this reminds me a lot of
this there's a tool called Alfred um
yeah yeah yeah yeah Alfred which is a
it's it's kind of like it basically just
looks like your Spotlight but it has a
bunch of different tools and you can do
all all the same kind of stuff you can
um you can you know have it run scripts
and custom handling and all that kind of
stuff it's very very very similar so I
imagine you could probably do the same
thing with Alfred on Mac yeah um for me
I like being able to like chain them
together and like have sort of the
flexibility that I have because it's a
programming language so because I'm
doing it in in Python I have all the
manipulation factors of like strings and
indexes and lists and like the subtypes
like the the Primitive types and stuff
that you have access to in Python that
make it easy to sort of manipulate data
in more ways then um like you could
technically do it with like the setup
that you have for me I can basically
just because they're functions I could
just easily like you know scrap
something together and it's a little
less and I guess uh you know yeah and
and I guess in a python context as well
you've got the you can press the up
button or whatever and it'll show you
the previous command and you can redo
the same command over and over again
rather than having to like save it and
then paste it and that sort of thing
I'll have to see if my my flow has like
a history thing but what I was thinking
was like you could actually just Define
a query in flow um
launcher dude Bagel is this cat yeah I
don't know if we told people I got
another cat her name's Bagel she's a
kitten then she's just like the most
curious little she looks like she's
hunting something right now she's so
cute I can't even deal with it man
interesting yeah yeah she's very very
cute um yeah but what I was thinking was
like you could use the
uh flow you know plugin system to
actually just be able to write all of
your stuff in the flow um in the flow
little box that pops up right and then
you have it just copy it back to I don't
know there's something really cool to me
about having something in your clipboard
and then modifying it and then you know
being able to paste it again uh or even
maybe having it selected and then you
hit something and and it does it because
it just makes everything a lot more
seamless I think so I about this I was
talking about this with somebody else
but I use my clipboard as like a buffer
basically like a temporary buffer like
all the time um and I use especially in
Python there's this um this module
called Piper clip yeah like it's
basically paperclip but py and it's it's
crossplatform clipboard reading and
writing and it's so so useful um because
you you know you just from Piper clip
import copy paste and then you have two
functions copy paste and they copy and
paste from your clipboard and you know I
yeah it's it's really really um awesome
because you can change stuff together
like you said you can basically you know
copy wrap it around something that reads
from your paste and it just transforms
your clipboard and you know makes
everything super super easy so I love
that kind of the little flows makes the
little helper functions all that kind of
stuff makes it so much easier it really
does do and I guess just one last
question on this note do you know if
power
toys has the capability to do python
based
plugins um I don't know about that but
the reason I brought up power toys was
because power toys uses the O this OCR
project and I think I sent it to you
it's called text CB okay um but you can
probably use that because you're on
Windows you can probably use that for
the OCR stuff on Mac I think there's
built-in libraries like the like preview
and stuff you know like um on Mac the
the OCR is like really really good I
don't know what they what like I think
it's an internal thing that does but um
it's it works really really well you can
just take a picture and you just text
from it oh just like oh like everywhere
yeah you can just like you know open if
you open a PNG yeah on your phone on
your Mac like it works the same on all
of them and basically if there's text in
an image it will just let you highlight
it and copy it out and no way yeah yeah
oh yeah oh my gosh dude freak you know
I'm pretty firmly antiac but you've been
kind of winning me over over the past
it's it's really good dude talking to
you every week for at least an hour and
a half you know that there there is a
lot of stuff that it just comes built in
and is simple and easy to use that I
probably would have to go and set up and
and think I'm so cool for setting up but
like then I realize everyone's got this
if you're just using Mac so yeah and
like the thing is I I I you know my
powerful computer is mainly My Windows
desktop but I really hate hacking on it
because it's like it's not that you
can't set everything up I think like for
almost everything there is a parallel or
even just you can install it in one way
or another using WSL or some windows
wrapper of the same tool or what but
like it's really just having to do that
extra stuff of like does this work on
Windows is this a Windows problem okay
what do I need to install to make this
work on Windows and now what do I have
to do to like make it work within those
bounds instead of on Mac I just feel
like most of the time if it's a some
sort of Unix based tool there's probably
a Mac port for it uh if not I can
probably install it from source and I'm
going to be good to go like you know
just like I would be on a Linux box um
and that's like that just makes things a
lot easier to work with but it's expens
it's expensive and like they tend to uh
have sort of planned um obsolescence you
know where the where they you know after
five six years your Mac is not going to
be as good as you know the ones coming
out now that's the same case for for
everything man I don't like I bought a
laptop in 2020 like a mega powerful 3
and a2k laptop and I was like this
thing's going to last me forever and I
can barely use it now you know it's just
thing you know when we're using it every
single day and we're traveling with it
to the live hacking events and that sort
of thing it puts some you put some miles
on the thing and you just got to replace
them every couple years I've kind of
come to grips with that yeah for sure
it's definitely like one of the more
unfortunate cost of doing business uh
within like bug Bounty is that like yeah
we use expensive
high power hardware and we used the [__]
out of it and it it we burn it into the
ground basically with with kaido now we
may not even need to use that high high
expensive highly expensive Hardware I'll
downgrade my RAM amount perhaps
seriously man there's no reason I need
to have 128 gigs of ram in this computer
that I'm on right now it's like this is
ridiculous is overkill from almost
everything except for opening just the
smallest burp project so crazy honestly
if if I could install if I could have
like a Hackintosh easier um like in an
easier way I would probably like cons
strongly consider doing that I really
only use Windows for like gaming and
like you know yeah makes sense well I I
uh I just want to bring that back that
conversation back around to bug Bounty
um about the launcher thing because I've
used it already today and yesterday well
and a little bit yesterday when doing
bug Bounty related stuff and it's so
handy for getting you know if you have a
system in place to be able to write
plugins quickly to transform data in
your clipboard uh or transform data that
you're highlighting or maybe even like
Joel does transform data that you're
sort of pasting into a you know python
module or whatever um it really helps
your reduce the friction of ideation
during exploitation and also you just
feel leap as heck when you're doing it
so I would encourage any of you guys
when you're like you know you're too
brain fried or you're too you know
in the weeds and you got to step out and
do something else for a little bit maybe
you might set up you know work on
setting up your launcher or your
automation setup uh when it comes to
this sort of thing I think I think they
get value for that yeah I will say also
like because of the way that you've set
it up where it's it's running python
yeah that means that it's extensible so
like you could take the stuff that I'm
doing all the functions and stuff that
I've already written you could just wrap
them in like a you know a script that
runs that function specifically could
you send that to me
yeah no for sure yeah I'll send you I'll
actually send you it because um I'll
send you whatever I have um and you can
you know you can basically just do that
where then if you want to use them sort
of in a in like a IPython or in the
console you can do that but you can also
run them sort of from anywhere we should
we should clean it up actually and
release it to the the uh critical
thinkers tier on Discord I think they'd
probably really like that yeah that'd be
good super down yep I have a module
called py hack so I'll um I'll send it
over to you sweet that sounds good um
all right well we already 20 minutes in
and we haven't even covered any of the
things that we were going to talk about
so let's get to the news um nice
old-fashioned Justin and Joel style
episode this time around we've been
doing a lot of guest and uh you know
master class and all sorts of special
stuff lately so um good to get back to
the the good old Justin and Joel
structure um yeah absolutely the the
thing that I had first on the news for
today was the CTF by fron Rosen that
went out December 15th
um there's been a Revival of CTF uh
particularly xss CTF on on Twitter we
see a lot of of releases from Jox car um
and frons and Matias and I I did one or
two um so it's really cool to see those
come back and this one that fron did was
definitely something I've never seen
before I actually didn't have the chance
to solve it before he released the
solution uh cuz I had a really busy week
but uh this is definitely a really cool
a really cool payload um did you see it
it's in the dock yeah I did I did so I
spent a bunch of time looking at this
and I was I was going down the down like
the right path actually because I
noticed um like I I noticed right away
that in the Escape for Rex function yeah
and this will make more sense if you've
actually looked at the challenge but
there there's essentially two parts
right there's Escape for ridx and Escape
for HTML mm and the Escape for Rex takes
in like the Rex parameter name and then
escapes it so it could be used as a Rex
and then the Escape for HTML takes the
value escapes it so it can be used in
HTML puts it in the HTML um does like a
match and replace and I had noticed
pretty early on that there was some
really weird replace they were using a
very strange syntax okay they were using
back dollar sign Ampersand and I I was
like what the [__] is that like that
that that's like super weird and so I
actually I looked into it and I found oh
you know it
references uh it references some like uh
what what was it like last it's a syntax
language for um replacing things the
match substring exactly yeah yeah so if
you're familiar with Rex you probably
know that like dollar sign number is
very common for replace groups like if
you if you have select groups dollar
sign zero is the whole match dollar sign
one is the first group dollar sign two
is the second group dollar sign 3 is the
third group so on uh but I had never
seen dollar sign Ampersand or any of
these these other ones I only knew about
the indexes yeah um and for named groups
you can also do like dollar sign with
like a name if you have a name on
assigned with the group but that's also
a less common syntax yeah and uh that
was kind of as far as I got like I'd
spent a bunch of time looking at um you
know possible like how it was escaping
and all that kind of stuff I had a
suspicion that potentially there was
something with the Rex but I didn't
really go down that then I got
sidetracked and never really got to
finish it and so when I saw that he
tweeted out the hint and was like dollar
sign I was like okay for sure this is
something with the Rex I just don't have
time to do this but that kind of
confirms my suspicion and then he he
came out with a hint and um when I saw
what the intended solution was it it it
caught me off guard again because it was
not just the dollar sign but also like
another nuance and so it was it was very
cool he linked out to um the Milla
JavaScript reference docs yeah and um
there's this section called specifying a
string as the replacement and this is on
the string. repace like prototype
function docs um and it says that
there's these different patterns dollar
sign dollar sign for dollar sign literal
dollar sign Ampersand for the match
substring dollar sign back tick for the
portion of the string that precedes the
match substring dollar sign apostrophe
for the portion of this the string that
follows the Matched substring and then
dollar sign n for the the numbers like
we talked about in dollar sign name for
named
groups yeah it's kind of crazy so much
functionality here it's like what the
heck yeah so I I really I haven't gotten
to mess with this yet but did did you
did you mess with it I I I messed with
it a ton and and well but after he
released the solution and I was like wow
this is super cool and whenever I see
this sort of thing it makes me think
like how can I look at this exploit this
specific scenario where this worked and
try to apply this to a a bigger concept
or idea and I and I and the thing that
kind of came to mind with this is like
input modification or input expansion
right like how can you take your user
input and and get it to do something
different or do something um what am I
trying to say or to modify the content
of that and we see this all the time
when you're bypassing
sanitization um you know we see this
when there's modifications being done or
functions being called on your input
after a certain check is being done you
know something like that those are
common patterns and this as well you
know anytime your input is being placed
into a scenario where it's being used as
um a modifier yeah as a modifier or as
like almost like code right it's like a
pseudo code it's not really code but
it's like a um could be interpreted as
string or it could be interpreted as
code you need to look at those
situations very closely because there's
almost always some weird [__] that can
go on yeah because I like I think if you
look at this challenge like in
retrospect um like obviously like I knew
from the very beginning like this isn't
going to require me to find a zero day
and Google tag manager yeah like for for
sure like there's not like he's not
hinting at a zero day this this is using
like the latest version like it's got to
be something about the implementation
that's one of the adventages about ctfs
and like challenges like this in general
that you know there's a solution so the
question is like what are you missing
and that gives you more opportunities to
sort of think creatively uh which is
what I really like about these types of
things yeah think critically
even um but I will say like
definitely your spidey sense probably
should have been triggered a little bit
if when you were looking at like how
this is working and seeing that it was
taking your input and making a Rex out
of it yeah well it's pretty much the
functionality on the page the the script
is only like what
35 you know lines long and when you look
at it everything else is pretty standard
um you know there's like 10 lines that
go to like parsing out a query string
and that sort of thing so pretty much
the only weird part of this situation is
uh the replace function um and and I
guess we we kind of dove into the
details and we didn't give quite a as
good of an explanation for those of you
that haven't seen the xss challenge so
if you're still hanging in you in there
with at this point thank you but the
scenario was that there was a a script
tag that was being dynamically created
um and what ended up happening and they
were using match string replace in
JavaScript for it and um what ended up
being the the the problem with this is
this whole concept of being able to
inject these uh what are they called
like group modifiers or into the replace
the replace portion of the replace call
um which will allow you to take the
preceding bit of what actually was being
matched so in this scenario that was a
script tag that had access to the double
quote character so when you put that in
that same double quote that was
preceding your user input would get put
into the replace text and then that that
would create that would break out of the
HTML attribute context and give you the
ability to insert a arbitrary HTML
attribute
which led to xss um it's super
interesting yeah like when I write it
redex I've definitely come across an
instance where I I understand why this
exists you know because often times
you'll try and match something before a
group or what and like maybe you need to
know what that is so you'll put it in a
separate group and then you just
reference it by its index or whatever
but instead this essentially takes the
default behavior that you can have a Rex
that matches a whole string but also has
groups within it and you can get you
know a
portion before that like before that mat
it it's it's a very Niche use case but I
I can understand why it exists and uh
I'm definitely going to have to look at
some of the bugs have submitted because
I think that yeah well and it it
underlies you know it emphasizes one of
the things that we've talked about here
often which is
reject they're used all the time for
security and they're very hard to make
properly secure so really knowing your
reject stuff inside outside upside down
in in PHP in JavaScript in Python in all
of these various languages all of them
have different quirks and uh this whole
concept of you know getting control or
being able to inject the pre- match
string and the post match string and
that match string in the result of a of
a replacement is something that you'll
Al also in other languages um and is
something that is more widely applicable
to Rex in general uh so whenever these
these sort of techniques come out you
got to go back and look at okay what
reports have I submitted that have
anything to do with Rex and how can I go
back and rebre it again yeah exactly and
there's always like um you know it's
good to to to know about these things
because some of these things are changes
within like how the default
functionality works these are
improvements or or things that you know
maybe this didn't ex I don't know when
this was introduced but um I'm sure this
didn't exist for a period of time and so
now it's been
introduced and uh now it's just
something that you have to sort of keep
an eye out for and be like okay this I
know I know now that like you can do
this you know put that in in my notbook
for later it's so common too like this
sort of templating thing where you're
taking user input and you're using it to
replace a a placeholder in a template
right like that happens all the time
it's not like some weird scenario where
oh you know the user's input is almost
never placed in the actual you know
replace portion of the of the Rex um
match and replace so anytime there's
there's templating this is something I'm
going to keep in mind because the
context is so important in those
scenarios and being able to inject
everything before uh your match and it's
not even that that that prepended string
is a part of the match it's not it's
just before the match so it it's very
odd and I I think it'll break a lot of
stuff so shout out to France for an
amazing challenge this one really this
one was really superb is the only word I
can come up with for it absolutely yeah
this is a very very cool one I liked it
a lot um all right let's uh let's take a
look at the next one here yeah oh man
this is this was nuts um this is the
hacker 1
disclosed uh 25k crit um which is kind
of nuts this is one of the things you
think you'll probably never see and then
you see it um but what what day was this
that they released this uh December 8th
hacker 1 disclosed a critical
ssrf on the analytics report
functionality in hacker one um and
essentially this was I mean not to
underscore or not to um you know
undermine the coolness of this
vulnerability because it was very cool
but it was pretty much a textbook uh PDF
render injection and he was able to
inject a iframe in in a PDF renderer and
that iframe was able to point to the AWS
metadata and pull AWS credentials and
just get access to everything um and I
just I don't know man I feel like I
would have I would have probably not
looked for this as much on hacker one
because of how crazy a bug this is and
you would assume that they'd have their
bases covered but I guess that's not the
case yeah I mean if you it's kind of
kind of wild because if you look at I
don't know if you expanded like the full
submission all the activity to look at
what the actual report was but like you
literally
just you know you create a new report
you choose some
filters and then in the
template uh or yeah you go to the the
analytics and you go to create a new
report and then in the in the template
thing you just you know you put you just
HTML inject and it's it's GG you know
go yeah it's it's super super crazy I
actually this is really interesting
because I was looking at this
functionality not long ago no way
definitely after no no definitely after
this was reported though it wasn't it
wasn't uh it wasn't before November 23rd
when this was first submitted but I was
looking at this functionality I was like
that's kind of weird why does it do that
um that makes a lot of sense this is
really interesting yeah yeah dude I the
fact that they was able to get an i
frame in there is kind of crazy and you
look at the explain and it's like he's
like all right Etsy password we're going
to hit uh you know 169.254 69254 he's
just like going at it and then the funny
thing too is if you look at the comment
he says I sent a message 10 minutes ago
to all of these Tri aers and he just
pings all of the tri aers that he can
think of which is amazing um but I mean
I would I would too man I'd be pinging
people right off the bat if I submitted
something like this so it just goes to
show man like even even crazy security
oriented companies that have had this
type of bug reported multiple times on
their own platform um you know can make
these sort of mistakes as well because
not all the developers are tied into
this and what kind of becomes um
everyday stuff for us uh doesn't
necessarily become that sort of thing
for all the developers even in a
security oriented organization so it's
it's encouraging to see and it it makes
you it kind of um refreshes the the
knowledge that everything's vulnerable
it just takes time you know yeah yeah
yeah for sure for sure so cool yeah it's
always it's always nice and I love that
they disclose all that kind of stuff too
so yeah that one must have been a hard
one for hacker one to disclose I don't
know if they if they like to disclose
that sort of thing I you know it seems
to me that they try to try to put forth
that that uh you know precedent for the
rest of the programs and stuff like that
but I'm sure ybert when he saw that
report kind of cringed a little bit
thinking all right gotta gotta send that
one to the rest of the ex but
no it's good it is good that they do
that um next I had on the list here uh
and I'm really excited about this one
kaido has finally finished the uh issue
that I
submitted months ago and I I I guess I
sort of cheated the system a little bit
on this one I submitted an issue to
kaido saying hey I'd really like the
search tab to be reworked and they're
like okay well you know we we prioritize
the issues by up votes so uh we'll get
to it if if it gets up upvoted I'm like
hm I think I know some people that would
like to upvote this and so I I ended up
like tweeting out and calling on some of
the critical thinking listeners to go
upvote it and all of a sudden it like
skyrocketed to the top of the upvoted
list to get a a cool search
functionality included into kaido which
is a very needed functionality I think
um yeah and they did it they did it they
prioritized it so um kaido now has this
really awesome easy to use just search
bar um and it's got also a wire
shares query language associated with it
where you can query specific parts of
the request um in this URL bar in this
sort of search bar um inside of of kaido
so I was really hyped about that I've
been using it a lot and it's been Mega
helpful and man the only thing they need
now is is plugins and then I'll be saded
for a little while I won't be knocking
on their door every day being like Hey
where's my feature where's my feature so
yeah dude uh I just need better
scope management that's like scope
management and plugins let me let me let
me let me add a caveat to that man they
messaged me after we had we talked about
that on the Pod I don't know if we've
released that episode yet or not but um
and they said dude we you can do that
it's just star the the word that you
want Star and I tried it and it works it
doesn't say it little document no
apparently it's been like that for a
while and they don't say it in the
little documentation if you click the
little question mark next to that
section
in the preset scope uh area but I tested
that and it wasn't like that so I think
that might be might be a bit of a change
but it it used to be that like because I
I have a habit of when I add a domain I
do like say it's example.com I add
example.com just by itself and then I
had star. example.com and that catches
both like root domain and then like any
of the subdomains under it because
sometimes you'll go to example.com and
it'll send you to dubdub dub.
example.com I thought you were doing
just example star you know no I mean now
I will yeah now I'm gonna do it just
like I do in burp because now oh that's
what you're doing in kaido gotcha gotcha
yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah no that
makes sense yeah you should be able to
do the same thing that you're doing in
burp now in kaido uh with just star word
star and that will give you anything
that has the word in the host name um so
that's a big Improvement I I'm happy to
see that so uh it looks like the wish
list for both of us now is kind of down
to those plugins so it will be great to
have some python plugins though I I love
I love a good
extensibility yeah for sure and I'm
looking definitely Jo is distracted okay
great that's good that's good I like to
see it w validated right here on the
from the cred team I uh I like I like to
see when stuff works so yes that's
definitely that's definitely
awesome good [__] man all right let's
jump over to the last thing on the news
um we had the
blind not blind I almost said blind xss
it's blind CSS exfiltration research
released by ports Sager and once again I
just wanna just want to say just because
I'm a kaido fanboy and I love kaido
doesn't mean I have anything against
ports sger as a company their product
it's heavy you know it requires a lot of
uh RAM but it's amazing and and burp is
a phenomenal tool and ports Wier
research is so great um and this time
around it was Gareth uh releasing a
blind CSS injection tool which is such
an interesting Concept in a relatively
new I guess attack vector or
vulnerability type not not something
that I've heard about before this uh
this write up uh where he releases a
tool for essentially being able to do
for it's like what xss Hunter is but for
CSS and being able to exfiltrate the
contents of various input fields and
text areas and that sort of thing uh and
the write up is really detailed and
includes a lot of
um I guess sort of research mentality in
there as well which is something we
really like to see about how he figured
out how many um input Fields there are
by using the has and not selectors in
CSS and then be chaining that together
with uh the what is it uh sick cyclical
import chain I want to say it's called
technique sort of coined in My Mind by
donut Al although there's another
researcher Pepe V that was also released
something almost the exact same time as
donut about CSS exfiltration um and
using the import uh sort of directive in
CSS to along with some delaying in
responding to http requests in order to
create a chain where you can exfiltrate
data very quickly and effectively out of
um CSS via CSS out of input Fields so
really cool research here you love to
see it uh and I'm excited to give it a
shot I haven't used the blind uh CSS I
almost must said blind xss again because
it's just a habit the blind TSS xfil
trator yet and I'm sure the use cases
are pretty Niche but I guarantee you
will see this at a live hacking events
sometimes because people always come up
with the craziest [__] yeah yeah no dude
this is U I Love This research this is
such a such interesting stuff it's
awesome they actually shouted out to
Donut and pepea um did in the in the uh
in the research that this was uh you
know this sort of this technique um was
based on that that sort of work uh the
import chaining stuff so so it's very
very very cool um I think CSS I I mean
we can kind of tell based on how Gareth
has been doing CSS research for the past
like two years that CSS is definitely an
unexplored territory and there's a lot
of really interesting stuff there and
they keep adding functionality too right
they keep making it easier they're
adding more selectors to do different
things with CSS instead of having to use
S CSS or uh what's the other I don't
know you see in yeah or whatever um but
yeah it's uh it's really really cool
stuff I love this this kind of research
so yeah I've I've as on the note of CSS
sort of features expanding I've got a
couple areas in my pocket where because
I was doing some CSS based stuff as well
when I was doing the post message based
uh CSS injection to credit card
exfiltration exploits and I've got a
couple areas uh on high impact programs
where I can inject CSS in an in like a
credit card
number context uh but I don't have all
the gadgets I need to fully exfiltrate
the card data so I'm just waiting and
waiting and waiting there are a couple
key features that I need CSS to release
before I can actually start to
exfiltrate that data so I've been
keeping a close eye on the CSS change
logs because I know they're going to
come out and some of the stuff one of
the keys I can think of in
particular they say that they're going
to release it and I'm just like when
please release for Christmas please so
that's funny there's some large
companies out there who are sweating
bullets right now just knowing that
their their credit card flow is insecure
just W for the CSS
release all right man um so that's it
for the news this time and what I was
thinking for the rest of the show is to
talk a little bit about the past year in
bug Bounty for the both of us how our
stats kind of
landed um if we're satisfied with
our performance over the past year and
also talk about some of the top earning
bug classes that we were able to
identify and then also sort of go after
some goals for the new year I I I'm a
little bit of a some people say you know
you shouldn't talk about your goals and
stuff like that in public before you
accomplish them because you get that
sort of adrenaline hit by saying all
right I'm going to do this you know and
that kind of takes away from the
motivation but I I kind of I kind of get
the opposite I'm like if I call my shot
then I got to I got to do that you know
and uh yeah it's so it's a little bit
scary to come on a podcast you know with
several thousand people listening every
week and uh and sort of talk about it
but we'll we'll see we'll see how it
goes I've I've definitely got some stuff
I want my I've got my eye on and I think
is the most effective way to accomplish
my bug Bounty goals but we'll see if
that changes as we as we get into the
new year um but first let's do the year
in review um do you want to go first or
should I yeah sure we'll we'll start
small here because I'm not the full-time
hacker you are so yeah so I um my
breakdown was um I submitted just under
25 reports uh 23 reports this year um
which is pretty good that's you know
about one every two weeks give or take
um so you know that's that's pretty
solid considering I work a full-time job
yeah um you've had a busy year too
promotion crazy bus Year all sorts of
crazy things so many Weds stuff like
that yeah yeah two cats in under year um
yeah so 30% crits 177% High 34% medium
133% low 4% none so yeah I'm about even
between highs and crits or sorry between
mediums and crits which kind of tells me
that basically I either end up in the
middle or I end up way at the top exact
yeah yeah so so that's kind of
interesting um maybe it would be good to
spend some time trying to focus on
seeing I can get some more of those
highs next year cuz I mean high high
payouts are usually still quite good um
so you know it's not not all about
focusing on that I think this makes
sense too because a lot of times when
you look for critical
vulnerabilities you and but there's some
like major precondition that's needed or
mitigating Factor you land at a medium
instead of a high which is a little bit
of a shame but it is something that you
see pretty often so it makes that makes
sense to me that about those would be
about even because about half the time
they're going to have some weird thing
that you can't quite work around or or
even you know when we work together um
you know there's some some preconditions
that were required for some exploits
that we just really couldn't work around
and because you can't really do anything
if you don't have access to
functionality and sometimes that
functionality is gated behind you know
uh privileges or something like that so
right right absolutely yeah um so the
breakdown for what type of engagements
are mostly on um it was basically 50/50
for me I'm excluding some of the smaller
stuff but it was essentially 50% Bounty
programs and 50% challenge programs uh
which is going to be like live hacking
events H1 C's the maybe I don't know
pentests are included in that maybe
maybe not I don't think I don't I don't
know um but yeah about 50-50 between
live hacking events and Bounty programs
which is pretty much expected for me
that's basically all I do for bug Bounty
is that and then pentest is a is the
little bit of the portion that's on the
side that's probably not in there yeah
yeah so I guess that's that's true
pentest are not probably included in
these stats which is interesting I I
haven't done many pent tests but I know
you do them on a pretty regular basis
right yeah I try and um keep him going
on somewhat of a regular cycle it's just
a good you know you can do them at the
same time as you do bounty stuff if you
have the um the the capacity for it and
I think it's a good source of income
like even if you're just a pentester and
let's say you book them backtack every
two weeks uh I want to say the pay is
let's you know it's a couple thousand
dollars per pentest uh per person so if
you you know multiply that twice a month
24 a year you know it's even if it's you
know $2,000 per pentest right that's
almost 50 almost 50k a year right so
that's awesome um it's it's a good
amount of side income if you can do them
all the time yeah that's that's great
dude I'm I'm uh yeah I think the other
thing that comes to mind on this sort of
thing is that you've mentioned in the
past that you feel like the areas that
you research take a lot of upfront
investment so it's not as easy for you
to just kind of hop in and say all right
I've got three hours let me go find a
bug you know it's more like all right um
I'm gonna hack this target now this is
going to be my thing for the next two
weeks uh and uh I'm only going to think
about that and that's going to be my
life you know like yeah one of the
interesting things I've noticed about my
hacking style is that like it's not
it's not so much like like the Bounty is
cool and stuff but I'm more enticed by
The Challenge and so when I see
something that's like been set up to be
challenging that's what really will get
me like I want to get around that so a
good example and this is a public
program Hyatt um Hyatt is uh they have a
bug they pay pretty well it is yeah yeah
yeah high at hotels um they uh they pay
pretty well H I think they have 10K
crits and um I was spending a lot of
time looking at their mobile app and
it's very very intensely obfuscated and
that just has got it's really grinding
my gears you know cuz I'm like I want to
know I want to know how this works I
want to dive into this I want to find
like what what's the juice that they're
hiding behind the the you know the walls
or whatever so um It's that kind of
stuff where but it's like huge upfront
investment like you said like I'm gonna
spend maybe more than a month just
trying to figure out how this kind of
this stuff is working and get the ins
and outs but once I'm there right I'm
ahead of everybody else so that's that's
kind of the the risk reward right is
that once you spend that time and you
get past that you get the understanding
it t takes everybody else the amount of
time to get there too I know that this
is a little challenging for you but when
you do something like this you should
probably stick with that program for
like a year Joel you should probably
like not just throw that whole
investment in the trash and move on to
the next program the next time you see a
shiny object I see how it works I'm
figured out I'm like okay that's cool
what what next yeah finally you know
Joel presses Enter he sees the the code
sweet okay well what's oh I got a
private program invite you know I wish I
was lying because like that is honestly
like that's how like the dopamine feels
where I like I'll finally like I'll
solve it and then I'll be like oh all
right well that's not exciting anymore
like what now what what do I go like
figure out how this works now so I do
need to I need to need to work on that a
little bit I uh we we we we'll talk a
little bit more about this in the goal
section but I'll I'll let you go ahead
and why don't you give your youreview
and then we can I'll I'll I'll do mine
and then we'll strategize together on
how to solve your bug Bounty my ADHD HD
yeah um okay so for me
2023 um you know I actually didn't
compare it with last year uh I kind of
wish I didn't either I kind of wish I
had done that so let me see can I
actually just press this and change
it
uh so yeah it looks like my last year
was actually slightly better than this
year uh as far as performance goes uh
and I'm going to go ahead and
reselect the correct items here but
because I don't I don't have the whole
thing up for what it looks like for last
year but just a quick look at the
numbers suggests that last year was
slightly higher performing than this
year um but this year I had exactly 100
submissions which makes me feel great
and I I can't submit any more bugs in
2023 now because uh I I'm locked into
that have to stick with that um which is
really cool I got
125 uh payments which means that it's
kind of weird it's kind of odd that they
say payments because it could be
multiple uh bounties on the same report
that's happened to me quite a few times
it could be collabs uh that I I've been
paid out from or they could be talking
about payments as in like uh how many
times it actually paid out to your bank
account in which case I know at the
beginning of the year they were capping
payouts at 10K so um that's that's a
little bit odd but uh yeah any
combination of those um and then my
breakdown as far as severity was 18%
critical 26% high 46% medium 6% low and
4% none um and I looked into the none
and I was like man did I really like not
even care enough to assign a severity
rating to this before I submitted it and
I believe those 4% none are like
reimbursement reports and stuff like
that for purchasing Hardware or like um
getting bonuses for doing well at a
specific thing you know they sometimes
ask you to submit a report and they'll
close it um and they'll just pay you a
bonus on top of that so that's what
those were I was really surprised to see
I only have 6% low um but I went back
and looked at it and it seems like it's
accurate um there's not very many bugs
that actually came through as low in the
end um and I think another part of this
is that there was a lot of dupes as well
that might have been paid out as lows
but they didn't care to adjust the
severity from medium to low uh because
it was a dupe so they just didn't bother
to change it so that could be where some
of the thing is to where most of those
are landing in medium um rather than low
and that low number is looking
artificially low um but yeah I was
pretty happy with 18% crits I went back
and looked at it and those are all like
true crits um which I was happy about um
and I feel like the crit to high ratio
is pretty solid as well um and kind of
expected for where this will lay out um
so I was pleased with that distribution
um yeah dude I mean I I was just
comparing while you were while you were
given your your rundown I was just
comparing my mine to last year yeah and
I think I must have had like a slump
last year or something cuz I I mean I
didn't even submit a crit last year
no and and I I Forex my bounties between
last year and this year really wow
congrats dude so definitely uh you know
don't uh don't let one bad year ruin
your uh you know your your mentality
because uh you can definitely get into
little slumps and not have the best year
but next year you know look forward to
next year right what what did you not do
right this year so actually let let's
let's go over that because um I think we
both put some goals together here um to
kind of go over like maybe things that
we could do better next year work on
next year one other thing before we hop
into goals that I wanted to share was
that the the challenge um The Challenge
to bug Bounty ratio that you mentioned
before was a lot higher for me it was
73% challenges and 26% bug Bounty uh and
so 70 roughly 75% of my reports were
being submitted to hacker One Life
hacking events or hacking challenges or
campaigns or something like that which I
think is pretty telling because when
you're doing the live hacking events
every other month you know uh there's
rarely enough energy for you to put more
time into other programs and I think
probably this 26 uh you know percent I I
want to say this percentage would be
even higher if we look earlier in the
year before Q4 um where the bug Bounty
live hacking events sort of slowed down
a little bit um I was focusing more on
other programs um yeah so really the
predominant amount of my income is
coming from the live hacking events
which is a little bit scary for me
moving into 2024 because
uh I'm I'm hoping to start a family in
2024 and I know that that's going to be
really busy and I might not make it out
to live hacking events quite as much so
yeah we'll see how that manifests but
there's always the opportunity to
participate remotely too so I think I'll
I'll probably be taking advantage of
that yeah dude for sure if you actually
change your breakdown from like yearly
or whatever to quarterly you can see
that over time like I see it in mine as
well where there are basically large
spikes where it's just like all
challenge like that whole quarter is
just like all challenge submissions or
maybe mostly challenge submissions um so
yeah I I have a lot of the same thing I
think it's just very difficult to
balance it right where it's like you
know you want to take time off too and
like not just be like hacking 24/7 so
after an event that's a great time to
take a little breather and then usually
the next event sort of starts to come up
and then you're doing prep and here you
go again right so um yeah it's really
cool and just to be clear um for those
of you listening the the graphs that
we're looking at can be found at hacker
one.com haacker dasboard boards SL
performance so if you go to your hacker
dashboard there's a performance tab at
the top you can find easy way is just on
that little sidebar or whatever in the
menu you click dashboard and then
there's a tab at the top called
performance and that'll give you all the
the graphs all the breakdowns you can
change the time ranges you can add
filters you can see your overall numbers
all the all the everything that you can
imagine um should be there so check out
the other stat that I wanted to talk
about is uh the payouts by bugs for me
um and I'm I'm curious to hear yours too
Joel but for me I was looking at the the
bugs that I made the most money on this
year and it looks like idor is like a
substantial amount of my income let me
run the numbers roughly in my head it's
like a sixth one sixth or 17th of my of
my income comes from idor um one I had
one huge xss payout so uh xss is my next
one uh but it would be a little bit less
if I didn't have that one huge xss
payout um and then the next one is
improper authentication generic and then
I think beneath that as well is the uh
broken access controls stuff um and so
those are the big categories for me
which kind of shows my testing style is
is largely um oriented towards some some
client side but oh also the other one on
here was information disclosure is a
huge one um and so my my my style is a
little bit moved towards information
disclosure and idor and access control
stuff as well as authentication um and I
think code injection came in at like
fourth or fifth um on the list so that
one that one makes a an appearance as
well but um I'm mostly looking for Au
authorization and authentication related
issues along with client side stuff yeah
so for me my top one was a privilege
escalation I'm not really sure I have
some ideas as to why that probably is I
think a lot of things probably fall into
that pry what I've been looking for the
next two which are kind of what I would
expect um excluding no weakness I I have
a lot like my third highest one is no
weakness so I either I'm not setting it
or each one's not setting it I think I
always said it though I yeah it's broken
you know I
promise it's not me okay but the the
next two named ones are information
disclosure and insecure storage of
sensitive information right those are
basically the same on my list as well
yeah and I kind of view those as
essentially pii right so it's uh user
data user pii um maybe a lack of access
controls that's leading to pii
disclosure or something like that so um
those two kind of make sense um and then
everything else you know I've got some
OS command injection reflective xss
couple you know functionality
bypass who knows what that is more
random things this is a little bit
challenging I think this is an area that
hacker one could improve on as far as
class if ific of bugs go and kind of
helping us um sort of formulize or um
organize our our hacking data to
represent what kind of vulnerabilities
we're finding um because these
vulnerability categories are so large
it's kind of hard to select the corre
correct one uh and then also when you're
writing the report the last thing you
really want to do is like spend time
scrolling through this giant like list
of you know 200 different things you
could select for the weaknesses uh when
you're just trying to get the report in
and you're excited and you're kind of on
that high so uh I think this is the best
data we've got and and it's definitely
an improvement from last year you know
the way that they were doing the
dashboards and stuff like that over the
past couple years um but I think there's
definitely still room for improvement
here yeah yeah absolutely it's uh it's
nice to be able to see this breakdown in
in in the granularity that we have it
let's uh let's let's talk about the
goals for for 2024 um you you want I
guess you started on the uh on the year
in review so I I'll start on this one um
yeah yeah go for it so and actually I
wanted to kind of talk through with you
something sort of as a friend talking
about goals for 2024 so obviously the
podcast has become a big part of my life
uh in in 2023 because we launched it
early 2023 and we're coming up on the
one year anniversary of launching it
around this time last year I was
messaging Joel being like hey man maybe
we should start a podcast um and so
that's cool
um with that I am trying to think about
what is the best technique or the best
approach to bug bounding for this year
that will give me the best Roi for bug
Bounty and also for critical thinking
right and and so I want to be able to
tell you guys about cool stuff every
week and I want to come in here pumped
you know like I've just found a bug and
share some awesome technical [__] with
you guys and just kind of share that joy
that comes along with bug Bounty um and
I think probably the best way for me to
do that is to try to bring research a
little bit more into my flow because I
could go in there and I could find a
bunch of Access Control issues and idors
and stuff like that and sometimes those
are really engaging bugs that are really
exciting and very fun um but a lot of
times those also just kind of pay the
bills and what's really more exciting is
like oh wow um if I'm replacing a string
I can actually insert the prematch into
the replacement by using this syntax and
just being like boom my mind is blown
you know and and bringing these sort of
cool tips and we've talked a lot of
stuff about about a lot of stuff client
side quirks and and post message related
stuff that's really exciting so I think
in in 2024 the best way to add value to
my own wallet as a book Bounty Hunter
and add value to critical thinking is
probably to do more research oriented
stuff what do you what do you think
about that yeah for sure I I think um
doing like cool unique sort of like
taking techn and like finding the
nuances especially for like bug Benny
we've talked about this a little bit
with like there's some blog posts out
there that are like here's all the ways
to do XY like window and top and like
all the ways to reference
window kind yeah right like it's very
difficult to find that kind of stuff
unless you found it and bookmarked it um
and so like going the extra step and
like being like we there's no research
on this let's create research on that
and let's give it to the community um I
think that is a really powerful
opportunity to like share knowledge um
unique knowledge and and research and
get cool opportunities and ideas and all
that kind of stuff plus find cool bugs
I'm I'm a little bit Unsure how that I
mean obviously I could pick a specific
area and then come up with like a sort
of artificial scenario and then do you
know e exploit that scenario and and
have that be the research but the kind
of way I've done it up until this point
is like let me look at an actual Target
let me look at the way that people are
actually implementing things break that
and then turn it into research and so
I'm I'm wondering if I'm not doing
enough on the turn it into research part
or and obviously we've had a lot of cool
stuff to talk about this year so I I'm
I'm satisfied with that and it was it
was a great year but I'm wondering if I
should approach it more from like a
actual research perspective or if I
should focus on really attacking what's
in front of me and attacking what I know
is actually being implemented by these
you know 20 20 to 30 companies we assess
every single year yeah so I think I mean
a lot of this a lot of the research
stuff comes like naturally right so what
what happens is you'll like spend some
time exploring something maybe it goes a
little deeper than you might have
expected and then you kind of are like
you know I've seen this on other apps
like let me spend let me spend some time
like figuring out how this works and
like finding this bug across other
platforms Etc um so I think
that is probably like I don't think
you're like underdoing it you know what
I mean I think as a full-time researcher
it's difficult to find the balance
between research you want to publish and
research you want to keep to yourself
and also then doing that research while
hacking all that kind of like it it's
difficult right
um so yeah I but I feel like overall
we're doing a pretty good job and we'll
just spend a little more time on like
some research I see it on your list as
well for the goals for 2024 that you
you've got unique research on there and
I think also one of the things in the
past is like I'm not
particularly a Twitter you know clout
person or or you know I don't I don't
have a lot of motivation to go and take
these research um things and write like
a massive blog post about it and then
post it you know to share it and even
though I would like to share it it's
just I don't see the most Roi for my
time in doing that um in the past but
now I think with critical thinking a
little bit more established and the the
the subscribers on the Discord and that
sort of thing there's a little bit more
of an impetus for me to say okay well
let me take one day you know one one
calendar day here and devote it into
taking this research and like getting it
into a document and then getting some
people to review it and that sort of
thing and getting it published um and so
we'll we'll see how that manifests
itself in the new year I think I think
we will see some more stuff come out
especially to the premium Discord and
and definitely to the world as well um
since we have a little bit more of a
focus on that now
yeah yeah absolutely um yeah I did have
unique research in there uh for myself I
I mean it's kind of what we just talked
about which is basically you know um I'd
like to find some you know Cool Tools or
cool you know architectures whatever
infrastructure you know I just want to
do some deep Dives on stuff figure out
how stuff works um and some of that I
think will be spurred by the ongoing
hacking and research that I'm doing like
outside um but also
just maybe from the community as well as
friends as we discuss and see different
things on the internet yeah and I I
think the whole just going back to the
whole conversation surrounding research
for research sake rather than research
for hacking a company's sake I think the
research for research sake sort of like
James Kettle style stuff is like is
super great but then you've got that
extra step of like all right now I've
got to figure out how to scan for this
across all of the book Bounty programs
and if you don't have like a very
identifiable fingerprint for that like
for example I'm thinking about doing
some post message based research sure I
can scrape all the JS files and find
every message you know reference to post
message or whatever but it's not going
to be every single reference to post
message it's going to be like a you a
very specific subset of those um so it's
a little bit harder to you know program
eyes that sort of thing um which I'm a
little bit intimidated by but also you
know you see some great results come out
of that so maybe it's something I should
try I don't know I guess we'll see
yeah yeah absolutely um let's see what
else we got L here yeah let me let me
I'll talk about this next one and then
we'll kind of go back and forth because
I've got a couple more than yours um so
the next one I have on my list is
non-traditional automation stuff uh that
I like to do in 2024 and that includes
JS monitoring which is something we've
talked about a lot here to kind of uh
alert when new features are being added
to applications that you already have a
large context for and source code
monitoring for things that you actually
have the source code for which I think
will be really big for me uh if I can
identify some vulnerable patterns in
open source software that's being you
either propagated to a bunch of
companies or is actually have having a
bug pounding program themselves then I
think that could be a a source of
semi-passive income where it's like hey
there's very likely a bug here go check
it out and it takes maybe an hour to
exploit it and you can get a report out
of it uh but it's not you know the
traditional uh subdomain take over or
whatever xss that you see in automation
yeah dude I feel like that that kind of
that kind of um pipeline is like really
really use really really useful for um
for those who don't see the cat Bagel
Miss Bagel is climbing on me right now
very cute very cute cat trying to nap um
yes but uh no I think that that kind of
pipeline is very very almost necessary
for full-time hackers because the
reality is if you don't have something
like that then you're going to be
spending time looking for things to hack
and that takes time which takes away
from your money hacking yeah right and
so like if like if you don't spend some
time building an automation or some sort
of monitoring or whatever that's like
constantly feeding you new things to
look at then you're going to have to
take your own time out of your hacking
or extra time right where you could be
making money to go then find those
targets or spend time looking at those
things and and track down those signals
and uh you know it just makes it a whole
lot easier for you uh to have basically
like a little assistant kind of who's
just like hey take a look at this take a
look at that and sort of refreshing your
context too because we kind of talked
about that before as well of like you
kind of lose context for a specific
program after a little while but if
you've written if you've taken notes
with code that was one of the big
takeaways that I had from Sam Herb's um
episode was if you've taken notes with
code and you've said hey there was a
reason why I thought that it was really
important that this I should alert on
this specific string and then those
neural Pathways refire a lot more
quickly and you can get right back into
where you were uh versus if you're
coming in with no context so that's
that's something I'm currently doing on
on a couple programs but the pipeline
isn't like fully built out and sometimes
my scripts kind of flake out or whatever
so that's something that I'll I'll be
doing more of in 2024 and getting a good
pipeline in place for um yeah all right
what's the next one on your list um I
wanted to be more consistent with um
reports and hacking uh I think we we
talked about that I I'm about you know
one every two weeks um right now I think
I'd like to get that more just in
general across the board I'd like to be
doing more hacking um submitting more
reports looking at more stuff um it's
very difficult to find the time and the
energy with all the million things I
have going on to um sit down and like
spend some quality time hacking and
finding bugs um I find that a lot of the
time I'm just kind of like looking at
stuff and noticing interesting things
but it it it takes a little bit more to
get it to to sort of that end point yeah
um so I I'd like to be a little more
consistent on that for sure yeah
consistency as a part-time Hunter is is
difficult because it ABS in flows with
your job with your personal life with
all this other stuff and the next one on
on my list is trying to accomplish all
of this like lofty goal stuff that I've
got for the podcast and for bug bounty
hunting in normal business hours in in
you know an 8 hour day because here's
what I've come to realize is
like you can accomplish really amazing
stuff if you work 80 hours a week and
it's not that hard you know besides the
besides the working 80 hours a week part
which is you know just physically and
sort of mentally challenging um if
you're working double the amount as as
other people you're going to have crazy
o you know oversized results right and
that's just kind of to be expected and
not that crazy the crazy thing to me is
when people work less
than other people or less than expected
and still get outsized results right so
that's kind of something that and that
that kind of shows that youve really got
your system down or you're really
looking at something differently you
know um or you got really lucky or you
got really lucky right which I feel like
that's the case every single time I
submit a bug but um the data would
suggest otherwise considering either
that or I'm the luckiest human on earth
um uh and so for me 2024 I want to limit
that and and really just work within a
certain period of time um whether it be
a sliding 8 Hour window or uh you know a
flexible 8 Hour window whatever it is um
and then just work more efficiently and
still accomplish great results within
that time
frame yeah yeah absolutely I think
that's a really interesting um takeaway
is like you know what you mentioned is
that like being able to do the same
thing that other people do in less
amount of time m means that you can do
more than them or you can make more than
them or whatever like and that's a
really like if you can figure out how to
optimize what you're doing to dude in
less time that's huge right so I I I
love that um I feel very similarly which
is like I'm doing a ton of things and
generally I'm pretty good about like
keeping it within work hours but I also
feel like the burden of doing all those
things makes it very challenging to keep
all them going at the same time yeah so
maybe it's you know rebalancing them to
do them on certain days instead of
everything every day um or or whatever
it is you know I'm not quite sure but I
think it's definitely something uh to be
worked on yeah and and just for those of
you listening that might feel
like you haven't achieved the sort of
success that you're looking for whether
it be in Buck Bounty or career and stuff
like
that one one tip that kind of goes
contrary to what we're talking about
right now is that if really you just
want the success one of the best ways to
get that is just put in more time you
know and and you got to decide whether
that's going to be healthy for you or
whether you're in a position in life
where you're going to benefit from that
um and whether that's actually what you
want with your goals uh but if you're
really just looking for Success you can
probably find that by doing it more and
I've noticed this in in multiple areas
of life you know um not just bug Bounty
but Fitness as well was one of the other
ones I was like I used to be doing a
three by five program where I would do
three sets of five reps and when I once
a week but then I switch to twice a week
5 by five and I noticed the results
dramatically changed just because I'm
I'm pushing more weight and I'm spending
more time doing it you know um and so I
think that's another hack but obviously
comes with at the cost of a bunch of
time and effort so yeah yeah the next
thing I had on my list was I want to
hack more iot stuff or I want to do more
hard core source code review and those
are not entirely disjointed from each
other but I'll just say Joel that
experience that we had of hacking uh on
that live hacking event together earlier
this year um and we just had like this
massive python code base and we were
just tearing it apart and finding all
the sources in syns and even now with
with the word fence stuff we've done
over the past couple weeks doing a lot
of PHP source code review and that sort
of thing um I just realized how much I
love actually having source code it's
it's phenomenal you know um okay dude I
have a I have a program uh oh for us
what have you got I've been I've been
working on something okay do you I can I
don't know if we should don't say it
don't say because I'd like to work on it
with you but it's a public program but
yeah oh all right well we'll see how it
goes I I would definitely like to do
more of that and I love the concept of
iot stuff being where like you dumped
the firmware and then you get the source
code and now you're doing source code
review that's the ideal situation but
this is going back to what we were
talking about before iot stuff the
bounties aren't good enough relative to
the time you have to invest really iot
bounties need to be high high five
figures to make it worth worth the time
if you're if you're a decent web Hunter
right because you can go to programs
like PayPal and Shopify where they're
paying massive bounties for web stuff
you know um and and find stuff quicker
than you would on an iot based program
and it's easier you know and your eyes
aren't bleeding and you're not having to
fight with hardware and there's not a
bunch of setup without the thought of
return on investment so I think iot
space needs to expand its bounties uh
and and pay a little bit more into the
five figure range and some even in the
six figure range to see the real big
sort of Attraction from other Hunters
that have diverse skill sets as well so
one of those two will be good and then
this is the other thing that uh I I
wanted to talk about and this is kind of
a I think probably something that you
and I both have on our our goals for
2024 would be um this concept of
influencing tool creation or influencing
uh the sort of development in the
industry that we'd like to see that we
don't necessarily have time to do right
so I've just been really Blown Away by
how awesome the critical thinking
Community is and how you guys have taken
a lot of the ideas that we've presented
here on the podcast and actually turned
them into tools um and I think that
that's something that could be scaled
well you know like we us in these sort
of things us having sort of the inside
scoop from a lot of top Hunters taking
it to the podcast giving it to the
public and then the public turning this
into actual actionable tools that can be
used by all hackers and making it a
little bit more accessible um so that's
something I definitely want to keep
doing in
2024 yeah for sure same here um you know
I I I want to I want to keep working on
that all that kind of like influencing
influencer this like a whole new yeah
like there's um this is a whole new
space I think for both of us so it's
it's definitely been interesting uh all
the stuff that we've learned in the last
year um and influencing little you know
kind of has a little bit of a negative
connotation but but really at the end of
the day it's it's educating you know
it's sharing knowledge right which is
what uh that this whole content creation
thing is about is like coming on here
giving that knowledge giving that okay
so there's the knowledge piece and
there's also the energy piece right
because you know you can come in here
and man like sometimes I've been on this
podcast and I'm like for grabbing my mic
so tight and I'm like yelling into the
microphone because I'm so hype about
these sort of things right um and that's
great that's great to share with the
community and the community has shared
with me that that that is a source of a
lot of a lot of energy um for them and
and can can lead to the development of
some really awesome tools that I've that
I've seen so uh definitely excited for
that yeah yeah absolutely and and the
last thing on mind was uh I I want to
hack more web stuff honestly I uh okay
so
we're I hack some web stuff yeah yeah
yeah it's we are basically flipping cuz
I've done you know a lot of iot stuff I
do stor C review like all the time like
it's all mobile is just like reading
code and like I've done a lot of that
kind of stuff and um it's not that I'm
bored of it it's just that like I I want
to do new stuff you know I want to learn
new things I want to get better at stuff
like I see I I feel like there's a a
part of like there's a there's a a a
whole bunch of vulnerabilities that I am
not good at um that I'd like to be
better at and I haven't been good at
them because yeah in the web space just
because like I don't do them as much
like I don't exploit them as often I'm
not looking at those Technologies as
often so it's just something that I'm
not as familiar with and um I definitely
would like to like to get there with it
so sweet man well we can we can trade a
little bit I I feel comfortable with
almost every you know web based
vulnerability that I can I I'm aware of
um and so we can we can trade off
knowledge there and you can teach me how
to do some good source code review and
and uh and iot hacking absolutely should
be great man all righty dude I think
that's a wrap you got anything else you
want to say before we kick it to
2024 no you know honestly this was a
great year um thanks to everybody for
listening to the podcast being with us
on this on this uh this first year it's
been really exciting and I'm looking
forward to what happens next year yep
same same here I really appreciate the
community and uh thanks for thanks for a
great year critical thinking listeners
yeah
[Music]
peace